[Jerry] Previously on
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee...
What car just makes you want to have fun?
An aqua '56 Vette.
-[Jimmy] This feels good.
-[Jerry] Yeah.
[Jimmy] It’s a Quentin Tarantino movie.
"It’s not who wants it,
it’s who gets stuck with it."
Now, the next thing I’m gonna do
is take off my pants.
[Jimmy] I knew it was gonna get weird.
[Jerry] But look
at the colorful shorts I have on.
[Jimmy] Oh, my god.
What do you think?
Makes you feel alive. This is great.
[Jerry] And now, the conclusion
of "Jimmy Fallon, the Unsinkable Legend."
[Jimmy laughing]
[Jimmy] I’m loving it, man. I’m loving it.
This is what it's all about.
Welcome to the best episode yet
of Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
This is exactly right.
-We're free.
-We're doing it right.
[speaking indistinctly, laughing]
You didn’t tell me I was going
to get wet on this ride at all.
-Look.
-[Jerry] We’re gonna get wet.
-[Jerry laughing]
-Look at me. Look at what I’m--
[stammering] This is insane.
Do you ever get really mad?
How do you express it
when you’re really furious?
[Jimmy] I used to be more of just like
snapping or just scream.
[Jerry] Really? You screamed?
-[screaming]
-[laughs]
Come on!
But now, the older I get,
I think it’s more, I just don’t, like...
It’s no one’s real fault.
-I go-- [laughing]
-[Jerry] Of course it is.
Like, it is someone’s fault,
but it’s not gonna help if I get mad.
Wow, really? You have that much control?
[Jimmy] I do now. Yeah.
What’s the hardest part
of doing the show these days?
-The hardest part?
-Yeah.
[Jimmy] I just want to make sure
that everyone’s happy.
Everyone’s happy?
-Yeah.
-Oh, God.
-I know, I know, I know.
-No one’s happy, first of all.
I know. I know.
And the last thing you ever ask anyone
who’s working for you is,
"So how’s it going for you on the show?"
-I don’t--
-Never ask.
-Don’t ask.
-‘Cause I’ll tell you the answer.
-It’s not going good, no.
-Right, okay.
[Jimmy] When I first started,
I could barely make it to six minutes.
Talking to somebody,
I’d be like, "We talked about that.
Yeah, we talked about the DVD,
and we hit that thing,
and told that funny story."
-And then I go,
-Right.
"We’re going to commercial."
And they go,
"We’re three minutes short."
-So I go--
-Right, right.
"I don’t know what to do."
Now, I’m so comfortable,
I just talk and just keep talking
to people, and next thing you know,
they’re like, "Yeah,
we’re like ten minutes over."
It’s fun.
I’m really in the zone right now.
Where it’s like, "Oh, I can do this."
[Jimmy exclaims, laughs]
That was insane.
Very nice, we got a "very nice."
That’s cool.
[Jimmy] Sarah Silverman
was coming on the show,
and we had a bit that we wrote
called "the perfect butthole."
The doctor found what he thinks
is the perfect butthole.
It wasn’t that funny of a sketch.
It was really weird,
and that day NBC announced that
I was taking over The Tonight Show.
[Jerry] Wow.
-We can’t do "perfect butthole."
-No.
Of all days.
‘Cause that would be
"the perfect butthole" thing to do.
That would actually be
the worst move I could have ever made.
You would get a call
and someone would say,
[Jimmy] "Really?"
"What kind of butthole are you?"
-And you would have to say, "perfect."
-Really?
[Jimmy]
They were making the announcement,
I knew, Jay knew,
Lorne knew, and that was it.
No one wanted it to get out
in the press.
We wanted to handle it...
-better than it was handled in the past.
-Yeah.
The press release was coming out
at 12... noon.
I was in the middle of a creative meeting
with the writers.
-Yeah.
-And we’re sitting there,
and I didn’t tell them
that it was just happening.
[Jerry] Wow.
[Jimmy] We're sitting,
looking at the clock ticking.
I was like, "Uh-huh."
And we’re doing bits with the writers.
I’m looking at the clock,
going, "Oh, my gosh,
I have three more minutes
‘til it’s official and I can tell p--"
I know, and I’m so nervous--
We’re going over jokes
and what bits are funny.
"I don’t know if you want
to do that with..."
Then it’s two minutes, then it was one...
[imitates buzzing]
All of a sudden,
everyone’s phones started buzzing,
and ringing and somebody goes, "Dude."
"What?" And I was like, "I know."
And then, it's just all over,
and the phone’s ringing,
everyone’s calling.
And people were crying and going, "What?"
and coming in the office,
tackling me and hugging,
like, "This is the best. You’re getting
The Tonight Show? This is crazy!"
[Jimmy] The other big moment is
when we could tell everyone
we’re staying in New York.
When we do our show now,
it’s like, we’re all just happy to be
where we are and have jobs,
and we all... I think everyone’s
in a good mood right now.
That is so amazing.
Yeah. Good spirits.
[Jerry] What was so stunning about you
moving the show to New York,
there’s a lot of gravitational pull
to LA in show business.
This is where it is.
Everything else is a satellite.
Everything else is a branch office.
This is where it really is.
-Yeah.
-And you went, "I don’t think so."
[both laughing]
[Jimmy] What a day, man.
We packed a lot of fun stuff in already.
-[Jerry] Yeah.
-This is awesome.
Do you get nervous with no seat belts
or airbags,
or any of that stuff?
How much have you
really used the airbags?
[Jimmy] I went to a bar here.
This guy with really tough
fisherman calloused hands.
He shook my hand
and it was like shaking a brick.
He goes, "Hey, would you do me a favor
and say hello to my wife when she comes
out of the bathroom."
I go, "Absolutely, no problem."
I go back to my table or whatever
and this guys sees his wife come out,
so I go,
"Hello." And he goes,
-"Excuse me. You're talking to my wife?"
-[laughing]
I go, "That's the type of comedy
that you guys do here?
Am I getting in a bar fight now?
Like, that's... You made me do this."
[Jimmy] The thing I’m looking forward to
is finding out new things from your kids.
At a certain point, you just
can’t be teaching your kids everything.
-You won’t be.
-You just won’t be.
No. You’ll never stay ahead of them.
It is fun how you’re so much smarter
than them,
and then they rocket past you so fast,
at a certain age,
probably like seven or eight.
So all of a sudden, you’re an idiot.
-You are an idiot.
-You’re the idiot.
I’m the one that just taught you
how to walk.
-Yeah. You couldn’t even eat.
-You couldn’t even eat.
Gosh,
and now you’re telling me what to do.
"Yeah, fix my phone."
"Give me your phone."
She goes, "Give me that."
Really. Just it’s sad.
Yeah. "That’s how you do it. You know."
[both laughing]
[Jerry] Have you had coffee yet today?
-I need coffee.
-Me too.
This is my favorite restaurant out here.
-[Jimmy] John’s Pancake House?
-You’re going to love it.
-[woman] Hi, how you doing?
-[Jerry] Hi.
-Good, nice to see you.
-How are you?
[Jimmy] There’s something
funny in anything, right?
Somebody has a bit
probably about everything.
You think anybody has a bit
about like the thinness
of forks and knives, thin metal?
I think that would be
a funny detail in a bit.
So, I take this girl to this restaurant,
and the forks are thin.
It’s a thin fork place.
[both laughing]
You’re on your way
to something else. Right.
-You throw that in.
-It’s good.
I can see she’s not having
a good time ‘cause the fork is thin.
[both chuckling]
I just licked my lips
and I tasted salt water.
-Do you realize we were in a boat?
-Yeah.
I had to do it first,
‘cause I knew if we came here,
and then I was gonna take you,
I would’ve been thinking,
I’m wearing a swimsuit.
He doesn’t know it.
Were you thinking that?
Were you thinking that
when you picked me up?
Yeah, well, I felt like
I was hiding some deep sexuality.
That I’m wearing
a brightly-colored swimsuit,
-You had one?
-and he doesn’t know.
That must be how women feel
when they get to have sexy underwear.
"Wait 'til he sees what I got on."
It’s the first time
in my life I felt like a girl.
Like, "Wait 'til he sees
-what I got on under my pants.
-Wait... [laughing]
-That’s what I’m talking about.
-[Jerry] Wow!
-[server] All right.
-[Jerry] Thank you.
What you want in a pancake is to have
the consistency of young, human flesh.
[Jimmy] It’s spongy, it has life to it.
You’re with a guy
with brightly-colored undergarments.
And you got soft human flesh
in front of you.
-You’re in a weird place.
-I’m looking forward to this.
This is really, really going to be
a great pancake.
This morning, I thought,
"I can’t do this. I can’t do a show."
You ever wake up and think,
"I can’t get in front of these people"?
Oh, always, yeah, yeah.
How close to the curtains opening
and you walking out
have you ever said to yourself,
"I don’t think I can do this"?
Right up to the curtain opens.
But do you ever just feel
like, "I don’t belong up there"?
I think once it opens,
this is exactly where I should be.
-Once you walk out there?
-Yeah.
When the light hits you, yes.
But sometimes backstage, I think,
"I don’t know why I even
picked this business.
I don’t have what
these people want to see.
They want to see a funny guy.
That’s not me."
[server] How’s your pancakes?
So good, it should be famous.
-It should be famous.
-[Jerry and server laughing]
-Oh, you’re so funny.
-They should. No, I swear.
I was watching
Saturday Night Live last night.
Why don’t you watch today?
You like to watch it when it’s on?
-It’s Saturday Night Live.
-Thank you.
John’s Famous Pancake house,
you don’t get the eggs and hash browns.
You’re a very literal guy.
When I did the impression of you, on SNL,
you came up with the idea.
You debating you.
I just did you. [imitating Jerry]
Like that. I can’t believe it.
[in regular voice] And you changed
your voice to come up to my impression.
-I know, I’m kidding.
-I know you’re kidding.
I know you’re kidding
about me kidding, I’m kidding.
-Want to go see a movie?
-Yeah.
[Jimmy]
I will never ever forget that, man.
You changed your voice
to become the impression.
You go,
"I know where you’re going."
So you started going, "I know, but the--"
-To make your impression better.
-I know. That’s what--
That’s what friends do.
I don’t know how
you SNL people-- You know,
because you were a fan,
and then you’re on the show.
I don’t know
how your head doesn’t explode.
It does, it did.
It totally exploded.
It was like, this is insane.
Don Pardo's saying our name.
"Jimmy Fallon!"
And you go,
"I can’t believe where I am."
So I never renegotiated my contract.
Turns out very stupid, stupid move.
No one finds that charming.
They just go, "Great,
you’re an idiot."
Someone else renegotiated,
they have a boat now,
and they go, "Hey, why would I do this?"
Don Pardo’s one of those guys
where his voice is his voice.
He’s not putting on a fake voice.
It’s almost like the bit
that people would do like,
"How does Don Pardo talk
when he’s ordering pancakes?"
Yeah. Yeah.
[imitating Don Pardo] "Great pancakes."
-Really?
-Yeah.
Backstage, I got to see him
in the hallways. We’re in same building.
[imitating Don Pardo] "Jimmy,
you’re doing so great on your show."
And I go, "Oh, my gosh,
that’s how he talks."
You could just see
a microphone in front of him,
and you’re like, "Are you on?"
I mean, what is he doing this for?
His voice was his voice. That was him.
I went to the Yankee game once,
World Series.
So I’m at the game with Lorne Michaels
and with Jack Nicholson.
Jack Nicholson’s the coolest.
One of those guys
where his voice is his voice.
It’s like saying,
"You’re you, he’s Jack Nicholson."
So we order a hot dog
and beer, and I get Cracker Jacks.
I’m eating Cracker Jacks,
and he looks at me,
he’s got sunglasses, and he goes,
[imitating Nicholson]
"Did you get the prize yet?"
And I go-- I swear to God...
I get it out, I open up the prize.
It’s a sticker, a picture of a snake.
He goes, "You know, when I was a kid,
we used to get metal things,
like tin whistles, stuff like that."
Then without even looking at me,
he’s looking out at the game,
he goes,
"Now you get a picture of
a [bleeps] snake."
Dude, it was like someone wrote it
in the scripts.
"Now you get a picture of
a [bleeps] snake."
The funniest part is that
he asked you about the prize,
and that he looks off.
That’s the melancholy.
-You look off into the distance.
-Looking off.
It’s all crumbling.
-Are you finito? Or...
-Yeah, I’m done.
-Okay, great. Thank you so much.
-I want one more...
-[server] Oh, my gosh.
-[Jerry and server laughing]
-That’s it, that’s all I want. Just one--
-Is that?
Thank you, thank you. That’s it, no more.
That's fine.
You think I’m going to lose it, right?
At one point, I crack.
The talk show host's life
is a sick science experiment.
"Let’s seal up a lovable human being,
inside a studio and make him
make five hours of television a week.
And see what happens."
"Let’s see what psychological issues,
personality issues, power issues--"
It will be fun. Just for fun.
"Just for fun,
we’re going to put Jimmy Fallon
in a tube, for 30 years.
‘Cause the human brain
has thousands of parts, like a car.
Something’s going to break.
Wonder what it will be?"
How cruel.
Let’s get back to Sagpone. Or what is it?
-Sagaponack. It’s Indian.
-[Jerry] Sounds like an Indian apology.
It’s like if one Indian accidentally steps
on another Indian’s tepee
and knocks it down,
"Sagaponack. Oh, Sagaponack."
If you looked it up on Wikipedia,
it means "land of the underground balls."
I think they meant potatoes.
I’m being serious.
Oh, because there's potato farms there.
-All potato farms.
-Yeah.
So I think that’s what they meant
by "underground balls."
Anyways, I don’t know.
The whole thing, it is--
Let’s hope that’s what they meant.
Let’s hope.
Either that or the mob got to the US
a lot earlier than we thought.
No disrespect, Sagaponack.
Okay, here I go.
[woman] It’s been a pleasure.
God bless you both.
-[Jerry] Thank you.
-[Jimmy] It was fun. Cool.
-[woman] Keep up the good work.
-[Jimmy] Thank you. Bye, guys.
-[brakes screech]
-[woman] He know how to drive it?
[Jimmy] No, he’s figuring it out.
-[woman] People usually do it for him.
-[woman 2] There’s a clutch, honey.
-Oh, my God. It couldn’t be more perfect.
-[women shouting indistinctly]
-[Jimmy] No. He's got to jump us now.
-[Jerry] I’m on it.
[Jimmy laughing]
Oh, my God.
I don’t want any more.
I don’t want any more of this.
[Jerry] I’m glad I’m with you,
you know why?
You bring out my good side.
I have a dark side,
but I can’t have it around you.
Same way I had to change the impression,
I have to change my personality.
To match yours.
-[laughing]
-[Jimmy] Thank you.
-[applause]
-[Jimmy cheering]
[Jimmy] All right, that went on
for 45 seconds too long, those ladies.
-Yep. [laughs]
-That was annoying.
Were you annoyed with those ladies?
Uh, yeah. Completely annoyed.
Finally, Jimmy Fallon gets annoyed.
That makes my day.
[Jimmy] I don’t even like practical jokes.
I don’t find them practical.
-If someone actually did a Punk'd thing--
-Yeah.
Or the... I wouldn’t sign the release.
I'd go, "No."
-Really?
-That’s how mad I am.
So mad that you pranked me
that I’m not going to do that.
And it’s unusable stuff.
And now the pranks on you.
-That--
-You've wasted a whole day of pranking me.
You know what I wanted to tell you?
I forgot.
[Jerry] What?
[Jimmy] I called you back.
They said, "Thanks for calling."
Or something, and I go,
"It’s the least I can do."
And you go, "What is that?
'The least I can do'?
Why would you say, 'It’s the least--'
Like, thanks a lot."
Right.
[Jimmy] I texted you dates I could do it
and maybe some suggestions
of different cars you might want to do.
[Jerry] Yeah, yeah.
And you didn’t text or call me back.
No, that’s the least I could do.
-You actually did the least you could do.
-Yes.
-Oh, my God.
-It’s to show you.
-I didn’t do the...
-No.
I called you and said,
"This is the least I can do."
I thought it was the least I could do,
to call you back.
Yeah, no.
I wanted to show you
that’s not the least.
The least he can do is exactly, you know.
[Jerry] Yeah. "I’ll show this guy."
[Jimmy] Show me what’s what.
[Jimmy] You know, I snuck on to the set
of your last episode.
-[Jerry] Oh, you did?
-Yeah.
No one checked us for tickets. And we
just walked in. And we sat in the crowd.
I have a photograph of me
and Dom Irrera in your kitchen.
And so, I took a toothbrush
out of your bathroom.
The blue toothbrush with white bristles.
-Do you still have it?
-I have it in a safe place,
-in a box somewhere.
-That’s so fun.
And I owe it to you,
you’ll get it before--
I don’t want it.
-What do you mean, you have to have it.
-No, it’s yours. You stole it.
It’s like the Born to Run thing.
[imitating Jerry] He doesn’t want it.
[Jimmy] "What am I going to do
with it? I’m stuck with it.
It’s not who wants it,
it’s who gets stuck with it."